Frederick Henry Osborn Papers 1903-1980 Mss.Ms.Coll.24
American Philosophical Society
- Frederick Henry Osborn Papers, 1903-1980; 8.5 lin. feet (Box 1-12)
  - Osborn, Frederick Henry
    - Concerning foreign policy, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Concerning Princeton Trustees, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Congratulations for promotion to Major-Gen., 1943; 2 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Diaries, 1918-1945; 21 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      Atomic Energy Commission; Political issues; World War I -- Impact on science; World War II -- Dachau; World War II -- Impact on science
      - Diary (Osborn, Commander of Advance Zone, American Red Cross, 1918, May 12 - Nov. 24
      - Diary, 1918, May 12 - Nov.24; 3 folders, typescript
      - Diary, 1942 March
      - Diary, 1943 Aug.
      - Diary, 1943 Dec. - 1944 Feb.
      - Diary, 1944 April
      - Diary, 1945 March
      - Diary, 1945 April
      - Diary, 1945 May
        Includes May 14 description of Dachau camp, 15 days after liberation
      - Diary, 1943-45; 4 folders, typescript
    - Diary, The General Assembly of the U.N. at Paris, 1948; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      - Vol. I:, 1948 Sept. 21-Oct. 23
      - Vol. II:, 1948 Oct. 23-Dec. 3
    - Diaries (excerpts), Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      Observations on: President Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt, George Marshall, Henry Stimson, Douglas MacArthur
    - Drawing of Osborn & Andrei Gromyko, U.N.Atomic Energy Comm., 1947.; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Embargo Committee, 1917; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Foreign Policy material, 1960s-70s; 4 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      Anti vietnam war views; Committee of Correspondence on a new Foreign Policy
    - Foreign Policy views, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      - George W. Ball
      - Zbigniev Brzezinski
      - McGeorge Bundy
      - William P. Bundy
      - Barry Goldwater
      - Philip A. Hart
      - George McGovern
      - William Proxmire
      - Richard S. Schweiker
    - Human Condition, 1973; 4 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Identity card, American Expeditionary Forces, 1918; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Inventionsre. Hydraulic transmission, 1919; 5 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Letters to Children and grandchildren, 1956-1965; 2 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Letters to Parents, 1917-1945; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      - Letters to Parents, 1917
      - Letters to Parents, 1918; 2 folders
      - Letters to Parents, 1919
      - Letters to Parents, 1920-1924
      - Letters to Parents, 1925
      - Letters to Parents, 1927-1928
      - Letters to Parents, 1920s
      - Letters to Parents, 1931-1932, 1935, 1937
      - Letters to Parents, 1939-1942
      - Letters to Parents, 1943
      - Letters to Parents, 1944
      - Letters to Parents, 1945
      - Letters to Parents, 1940s
      - Letters to Parents, n.d.
    - Living expenses, 1950; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Manuscript - Challenge to Life. Man's Fight for Survival, 1980; 4 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Memo on personnel in ETO (European Theater of Operations), 1944; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-1945; 2 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Miscellaneous writings, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Notebook of experiments, 1919; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Notebook of experiments, Jan. 1920; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Notes for Princeton Trustees, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Notes on Education & Morale, U.S. Army., 1943-1945; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - On Vietnam, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      Report by Harrison Salisbury
    - Oral history outline (of his life), Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Papers, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      - Paper - Absolute Weapons - The American Reply
      - Paper - Atomic Diplomacy, 1948; 3 folders
        A collection of speeches delivered in 1947/48, as Deputy U.S. Representative to the U.S. AEC, to groups in U.S.
      - Paper - Changing Demographic Trends of Interest to Population Genetics, Before Congress of Human Genetics, Copehhagen, 1956; 14 pages
        Human genetics; International Congress of Human Genetics; Population genetics; Population, demography
      - Paper - Crisis in World Population, January 1967; 8 pages
        Population, demography; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
      - Paper - Economics as a basis of living ethics, 1919
      - Paper - The future of man, 1969
      - Paper - Future of Human Heredity, (radio broadcast), 1968; 8 pages
        Eugenics; Human genetics; Human genetics -- Race; Lectures, public speaking -- Radio broadcasts
      - Paper - Galton and Mid-century Eugenics, (Galton Lecture, Eugenics Society, London), 1956; 23 pages
        Eugenics; Galton, Francis; History of biology, especially genetics; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking
      - Paper - History of the American Eugenics Society, 1971
        American Eugenics Society
      - Paper - Human Heredity and the Modern Environment (Vassar College), 1941; 12 pages
        Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking
      - Paper - Implications of the 39th Yearbook for Eugenics, 1940
      - Paper - Man, 1971
      - Paper - Memo. on corporation grants in the field of human biology, 1940
        in re. Carnegie Corp.
      - Paper - Memo. re. Foundation policy, 1936
      - Paper - Notes on Paradigms of Public Relations: The Case of Social Biology, 1974
      - Paper - Notes on the means to survival, (incomplete), 1969
      - Paper - On marriage
      - Paper - On his philosophy
      - Paper - On population & fertility, 1970
      - Paper - On religion
      - Paper - Regional Differences in American Births, 1935
      - Paper - Signposts for Foundation Survival, 1955
      - Paper - Social Morality in a Period of Diminishing Population, 1935
      - Paper - Social Science and Problems of Government, 1955
      - Paper - Social Science in the service of man, April 1951
      - Paper - Statement on Eugenics and the family, (Before Nat. Conf. on family relations), 1940
      - Paper - To what extent is a science of man possible, 1939.
      - Paper - The United States and the World Population Crisis, 1964
      - Paper - Where do we stop, (re. population control), Jan 9, 1961.
      - Paper - The world about us, 1954
      - Paper - World Population Problems, (Seminar, Council on Foreign Relations), May 1957
    - Patent application, (For a Transmission of power mechanism), 1919; 3 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Photographs, 2 folders; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Publications, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Radio broadcast - The Quality of Population, 1940; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Speeches, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      - Speeches - Address before Fifth Int'l Congress of Pediatrics, July 15, 1947
      - Speeches - Address before General Lee's staff, April 23, 1944
      - Speeches - Address before the President's committee on Religion and Welfare in the Armed Forces, 1949
      - Speeches - Address before School for Orientation Officers, Dec. 1, 1943
      - Speeches - Address before S.O.S. officers, Dec. 4, 1942
      - Speeches - Address before Adjutant General's School
      - Speeches - Addresses before Special Services Officers' School, 1942-43
      - Speeches - American Foreign Policy, March 23, 1950
      - Speeches - To the Artists of the Screen, The Stage, and Radio: Thanks from the American Soldier, July 14, 1943
      - Speeches - Atomic Energy Commission, 1947-1950; 5 folders
        Atomic Energy Commission; Political issues; Radiation genetics; World War II -- Impact on science
        - Speeches - Atomic Energy Commission, 1947
          Delivered while with the UN Atomic Energy Commission
        - Speeches - Atomic Energy Commission, 1948; 3 folders
        - Speeches - Atomic Energy Commission, 1949-1950
      - Speeches - Campaign of the United War Chest, Philadelphia area., Nov. 9, 1943
      - Speeches - Conference of Commanding Generals of the S.O.S..., Dec. 19, 1942
      - Speeches - On the Constitution of the U.S., 1919
      - Speeches - Dedication of War Memorial at Station Plaza, 1966
      - Speeches - Detroit War Chest, Nov. 3, 1942
      - Speeches - Foreign Policy, 1948-51; 2 folders
      - Speeches - Home Front Mobilization Rally, 1943
      - Speeches - The Make-up of the Healty Family (Am. Eugenics Soc., Philadelphia), April 1955
      - Speeches - Morale Services in the zone of the Interior, July 28, 1944
      - Speeches - Preparedness for War, 1942
      - Speeches - Soldier and Civilian Morale, March 20, 1942
      - Speeches - The Soldier gets his bearings, June 13, 1944
      - Speeches - The Soldier needs the U.S.O., April 12, 1942
      - Speeches - Suggestions for a Prayer
      - Speeches - Talk at New York Times Forum, Nov. 17, 1944
      - Speeches - Talk before Women's Action Committee for Lasting Peace, March 1947
      - Speeches - Talk on population, Oct. 1967
      - Speeches - Talk on Red Cross work in France, Spring 1918 (1919
      - Speeches - Tribute to George C. Marshall, March 1949
      - Speeches - U.S. & Russian Ideology, (commencement talk, Drew Seminary), 1947
    - Trusteeships, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Vietnam War advertisements (anti-war), Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - War Department, Separation papers, 1949; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - WW I registration, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Writings - Miscellany, Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
    - Osborn and Bajema - Paper - Eugenic Hypothesis, November 1971; 12 pages; Bajema, Carl Jay, 1937-; Osborn, Frederick, 1889-1981
      Behavioral genetics, IQ; Eugenics; Population, demography; Publication -- Social Biology
    - Osborn and Lorimer - The Dynamics of Population - Reviews
  - Osborn, Alice, 1965
  - Osborn, Earl, 1914-16,1965
  - Osborn, Frederick Jr., 1934-51; 2 folders
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1914
  - Osborn, John (in re.), 1947
  - Osborn, Margaret (Mrs. Frederick), 1913-1916
  - Osborn, Warren, 1916
  - Osborn, William, 1903
  - Osborn, William Church, 1914
  - Osborn, Mrs. William Church, 1916
  - Osborn family - Letters
  - Page, Arthur W, 1941-43
  - Palisades Park, 1956-73; 8 folders
  - Palmer, Ely Eliot, 1944
  - Parodi, M. Alexandre, 1947
  - Parran, Thomas, 1942
  - Patterson, Margaret, 1949-1950
  - Pease, Richard, 1914-1917
  - Petersen, Howard, 1948-1949
  - Petersen, L. A., 1949
  - Peyrat, Joe, 1946
  - Photographs
  - Pioneer Fund, 1937-54; 10 folders
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1950-1951
  - Pollock, Thomas Clark (in re. John E. Vance), 1948
  - Population Genetics and Demography - Fourth Princeton Conference, November 9-11,1967; 8 folders
    Re. Assortative Mating. Transcript of the meeting. Bruce K. Eckland, Richard C. Lewontin, William S. Laughlin, Theodosius Dobzhansky, et.al.
    Conferences and symposia; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Lewontin, Richard Charles; Population genetics; Population, demography
  - Population Reference Bureau, 1969
    Robert C. Cook. reminiscences
  - Population Studies Center, 1969
  - Princeton University, 1951-1959
  - Princeton University Press, 1950
  - Prorok, Count Byron Kuhn de, 1942
  - Pulwers, Jack, 1980
  - Railway Age, 1919
  - Rea, James C, 1943
  - Reed, Joseph V, 1943-44
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1951
  - Reston, James, 1976
  - Richards, W C (in re. Henry Ford), 1946
  - Rives, Bayard, 1915-1917, 1962
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1941-1953
  - Rockefeller, John D., III, 1968-1972
  - Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., III
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1971
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1967-1971
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1917
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1913-1941
  - Roosevelt, 1940
  - Roper, Elmo, 1945
  - Rose, John Clarke, 1946
  - Rosenzweig, Michael L, 1973
  - Rousselot, B., 1913
  - Rusk, Dean, 1949
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1949
  - Russian Institute, Harvard, 1950; 5 folders
    Clyde Kluckhohn, "Members of the Politboro, their Motives and Sources of Information."
  - Scheinfeld, Amram, 1973
  - Schieffelin, John Jay, 1940, 1962-1964
  - Schieffelin, Luise, 1914-1916
  - Schieffelin, Mary, 1915
  - Schieffelin, William Jay, Jr., n.d.
  - Schieffelin & Co., 1965
  - Schriltz, Dick S. von, 1980
  - Secretary of War - Advisory Board on non-appropriated funds, 1945-1946; 2 folders
  - Selective Service System, 1941
    Harry Stack Sullivan
    Gen. Lewis B. Hershey
  - Shockley, William, 1968
  - Skouras, Spyros P., 1959
  - Smith, Harold, 1941
  - Social Science Research Council, 1945-53
  - Society for the Study of Social Biology, 1975
  - Solbert, Oscar N, 1944
  - Somervell, Brehon, 1944-49
  - Spencer, Lyle M, 1945
  - Stein, Gertrude, 1945
  - Stevenson, Adlai E, 1956
  - Stevenson, Earl P, 1950
  - Stouffer, Samuel A, 1948
  - Stowe, Leland, 1945
  - Stuart, R. Douglas, 1941-47
  - Tennyson, Aubrey, 1913
  - Truman, Harry, 1947,49
  - Truman Library, 1973-74
  - Tuck, William H, 1916
  - United Nations Atomic Energy Commission, 1947-52
  - UNESCO, 1946
  - Unidentified
  - United Defense Fund - Citation
    - * Dwight Eisenhower
    - J. H. Doolittle
    - Omar N. Bradley
  - United Service Organization - Award, 1960
  - United Service Organization - Citizens Committee, 1941
  - U.S. Armed Forces Institute, 1956
  - U.S. Army - Information & Educational Association, 1947
  - U.S. Army - Information & Education Division (5 folders, 1941-55
  - U.S. Army - Information & Education Division - History of (2 folders, 1972-75
  - U.S. Army - Information & Education Division - Notes on Army Policy in Europe, 1945
  - U.S. Army - Information & Education Division - Report to Gen. Marshall, Aug. 1945
  - U.S. Army - "Information and Education in the Armed Forces,", 1949; 2 folders
    - * A report to the President, by the Prs. Comm. on religion and welfare in the Armed Forces.
  - Vance, Cyrus, 1980
  - Verdery, M. J. Jr., 1914
  - Vogt, William, 1972
  - Watros, Livingstone, 1944
  - Watros, Livingstone - Tribute to Frederick Osborn, Nov. 20, 1945
  - Webb, Derick, 1964
  - West, Dr., 1975
  - Weybright, Victor, 1972
  - Whittemore, Irving C, 1946
  - Wiggam, Albert Edward, 1936
  - Wilson, Mrs. Andrew., 1956
  - Wilson, Joseph C, 1967
  - Winter, Gilbert Paul, 1965
  - World Government, 1949
    - * Rex Stout
    - Christopher LaFarge
  - World War II - Anti war propaganda, U.S.
  - World War II - Radio Broadcasts, (in re. the political nature of them, controversy), 1944
  - Young, Donald R, 1977
  - In separate boxes: Day Calendars, 1918-19, 1929, 1939-69. (Box 13-15)